<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Sql on Christopher Diehl</title>
    <link>https://christopherdiehl.github.io/tags/sql/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Sql on Christopher Diehl</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <copyright>&amp;copy; &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/christopherdiehl&#34;&gt;Christopher Diehl&lt;/a&gt; 2022</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 08 Feb 2020 07:24:44 -0500</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://christopherdiehl.github.io/tags/sql/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Optimizing text search SQL queries on a Raleigh crime dataset</title>
      <link>https://christopherdiehl.github.io/posts/sql-optimizations-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 08 Feb 2020 07:24:44 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://christopherdiehl.github.io/posts/sql-optimizations-2/</guid>
      <description>This post builds upon the previous post. If you haven&amp;rsquo;t checked it out already, please do so here In my opinion, SQL is easy to get working initially, but optimizing SQL is a whole different beast. Thankfully, I recently had the chance to optimize a whole bunch of SQL for one of our critical platforms resulting in an over 300% reduction in execution time. While I can&amp;rsquo;t promise the same result for anyone following this article, I do outline some of my learnings on optimizing for queries on text columns below using the most recent Raleigh Crime dataset.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Examining Raleigh&#39;s crime data using SQL</title>
      <link>https://christopherdiehl.github.io/posts/sql-optimizations/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 23 Jan 2020 14:16:20 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://christopherdiehl.github.io/posts/sql-optimizations/</guid>
      <description>Background I&amp;rsquo;ve had the pleasure of working on a lot of different projects and while the language may have ranged from Java to Golang, most have communicated with a database using SQL. In the beginning of my career, I viewed SQL as a unfortunate neccessity, Professor Imilienski at Rutgers changed my opinion. His project and lectures showed us how to view the and analyze datasets in a relational database, and how SQL can be used to gather some pretty powerful insights.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>